<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phylo1_modules on 2021 FIRE-CB Training Modules</title>
    <link>https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phylo1_modules on 2021 FIRE-CB Training Modules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/intro1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/intro1/</guid>
      <description>*Note: This assignment has a number of associated questions you&amp;rsquo;ll find as you go through this that need to be submitted on ELMS. Some of these ask you to explain or guess why certain things may be the way that they are. I am not grading on correctness here, rather I am grading based on whether you have completed the assignment and put some thought into the answers. Feel free to discuss these with your group or with me in lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/intro2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://training.fire.tryps.in/phylo1_module/intro2/</guid>
      <description>Phylogenetics The process of evolution leaves traces in the very genes underlying all life. Mutations happen one or more nucleobases at a time, generally randomly. Through the process of selection, organisms with mutations which are beneficial are more likely to reproduce, organisms with neutral mutations with propagate those at an intermediate rate, and organisms with harmful mutations will be less likely to reproduce. As far as we can tell, time only moves forward, so this process of mutation and selection results in an ever-expanding tree of genetic information, as ancestor genomes split and their different progeny contain distinct mutations in different parts of their genomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
